<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Project Euler on Not So Fungible </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://jamieduerden.co.uk/tags/project-euler/</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 19:37:53 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Euler</title>
      <link>https://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/project-euler/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Aug 2015 19:37:53 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/project-euler/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re considering&lt;/strong&gt; teaching yourself to code, or even just to code in a new language, I heartily recommend you take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://projecteuler.net&#34;&gt;Project Euler&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s essentially a collection of user-submitted maths questions, sufficiently tricky as to require solving by a computer, but sufficiently unintensive that programs capable of solving them can run in a reasonable time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mathematics themselves are done by your code, but the real challenge lies in thinking through the necessary algorithms and program flow such that you can build something which fulfils the requirements. It demands that you understand the problem, the nature of the solution, and your language of choice well enough to communicate the requirements to the computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some are fast; a flash of insight and a couple of minutes writing and you have the answer. Some can take hours or days of plotting out and trying different avenues of attack, especially at the higher difficulty levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I shan&amp;rsquo;t show my work here, as it would defeat the point, but I encourage you to attempt a few problems. As brain exercise goes, it certainly beats Sudoku.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
