<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Duck on Not So Fungible </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://jamieduerden.co.uk/tags/duck/</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 15:30:09 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Wednesday: Cassoulet</title>
      <link>http://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/food-wednesday-cassoulet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Dec 2015 15:30:09 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/food-wednesday-cassoulet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I promised&lt;/strong&gt; quite a long time ago, now, to give you all the rest of my recipe for not-actually-cassoulet. The confit duck legs of the previous recipe are one component of this; today you get the rest. Lucky you! I suggest you do the legs first since they need several days to mature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The topping on this variant happens to be gluten-free, which was originally just because a friend of mine has this habit of getting rather ill when she eats bread, but turned out to be a rather tasty alternative to breadcrumbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; low salt. Nor is it low fat, low calorie, low sugar, or otherwise boring. Portion accordingly - this recipe will serve between eight and twelve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Beans&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ingredients&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three tins (3x300g) flageolet beans, drained and rinsed with cold water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Two (2) shallots, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One (1) onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quarter (¼) tbsp. fresh thyme leaves (removed from stalks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quarter (¼) tbsp. fresh rosemary needles (removed from stalks)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One (1) bay leaf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One (1) tsp crushed red chilli flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinch of salt, pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One (1) glass of dry white wine (about 125ml)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Procedure&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bit&amp;rsquo;s not hard. Toss everything in a saucepan together, cover (plus a cm or so) with boiling water, boil for ten minutes. Have a sandwich or something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need all of this, but not at the same time; strain the wet bit into a jug (which I&amp;rsquo;m going to refer to as &lt;em&gt;Jug One&lt;/em&gt; from now, because we like giving innocuous things important-sounding names. The rest you keep in &lt;em&gt;Bowl One&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right, good job. On to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Vegetables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ingredients&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;180g diced pancetta. You could buy pre-diced, or you could go down to the deli and have them cut you a chunk off the pork belly to dice yourself. I leave it to you to guess which usually tastes better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three (3) tbsp. duck fat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Six (6) carrots, peeled and sliced thickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One (1) onion, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One (1) shallot, diced&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One (1) small head of garlic, all cloves stripped of skin, chopped roughly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three (3) tins chopped Italian tomatoes, mostly drained&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Salt, pepper (as always)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Procedure&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start by getting your frying pan nice and hot, and give it a smallish spoonful of the duck fat to get cracking on. When you think it&amp;rsquo;s ready, add all the pancetta and fry until crispy. Keep it moving or it&amp;rsquo;ll probably weld itself to the pan, which is no good because those bits are nowhere near as tasty and there&amp;rsquo;s some evidence to suggest that burned meat is a carcinogen. Who wants cancer, hm?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it&amp;rsquo;s crispy, drain off the fat and transfer the meat to &lt;em&gt;Bowl One&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pan&amp;rsquo;s still hot, so add another spoonful of the fat and all the carrots. Season and toss until soft and golden around the edges, then the same again - out with the fat, carrots in the bowl with the pancetta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the last of the fat, you need to sweat the alliums, then (leaving them in the pan) add the tomatoes, simmer for about twenty minutes, then add to the bowl, stir, and cover so nothing escapes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Meat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where it really stops being cassoulet, or so my French chef friend informs me. True cassoulet should have sausage in it. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t really work for me, so I use duck breasts. Six of them, to be precise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Preheat your oven to 465K. While that&amp;rsquo;s heating up, lay out your duck breasts skin up, and score the skin and fat without cutting the meat. Shake a little salt over them, then flip them over into a roasting tin. Roast for about a quarter of an hour, then rest for five minutes; you don&amp;rsquo;t want to take much longer for the roasting or they&amp;rsquo;ll be tough, which is sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slice into cubes of about an inch, then add to &lt;em&gt;Bowl Two&lt;/em&gt;. Tip the meat juices into &lt;em&gt;Jug One&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Retrieve your confit duck legs from under their fat by warming them gently in the oven. Pull them into chunks with a pair of forks, and add those to &lt;em&gt;Bowl Two&lt;/em&gt; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Crumbs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ingredients&lt;/em&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;300g corn flakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;150g hazelnuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One (1) tablespoon rice flour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zest of two lemons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juice of one lemon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Three (3) tablespoons olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A good handful of grated parmesan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One (1) level tbsp of brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Procedure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blend. That&amp;rsquo;s it. Not much of a procedure, is it? All together in the food processor, blitz until fluffy crumbs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Final Assembly&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bowl One&lt;/em&gt; now contains all vegetable components, and &lt;em&gt;Bowl Two&lt;/em&gt; now contains all meat components.
&lt;em&gt;Jug One&lt;/em&gt; now contains all fluid components except water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Procedure&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your oven should already be hot from roasting the duck breast, so set it to 450K while you assemble the cassoulet in the biggest casserole dish you can find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover the bottom of casserole dish with half of the vegetable mixture, followed by all the meat. Top with the remaining vegetables so you have the start of a delicious bread-free sandwich. Add all the liquid, topping up with hot water if necessary until the liquid just shows through the vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cook, without covering, for 45 minutes to an hour, so all the flavours meld. Remove from the oven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cover the surface of the cassoulet with an even layer of the breadcrumbs. Scatter with a little brown sugar, return to the oven and bake for about 45 minutes, until the surface of the breadcrumb layer is browned and cracked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow to cool for an hour before eating; it will still be hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you go. The rest of the recipe. Rather large, and not really scalable, as such; best kept for dinner parties, funerals, and other festive occasions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food Wednesday: Duck Confit</title>
      <link>http://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/food-wednesday-duck-confit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2015 20:29:20 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/food-wednesday-duck-confit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This one&lt;/strong&gt; was actually done on a Sunday, but you&amp;rsquo;re getting it on Wednesday because how else does one maintain a new tradition?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Confit duck leg isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly complex, though there&amp;rsquo;s a fair bit in the sauce here, but it&amp;rsquo;s delicious and sounds impressive, if that&amp;rsquo;s something you go for in your food. Duck itself is a fairly versatile meat, so long as you don&amp;rsquo;t overwhelm the flavour. In this instance it&amp;rsquo;s paired with orange, which is classic, but there are an awful lot of options. This is also a ingredient in another recipe which I will at some point post here - cassoulet. Start three days early - if you want it for Saturday dinner, start on Wednesday night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Duck Confit with Marmalade Sauce (serves 4)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ingredients&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Four duck legs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Juniper berries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half a head of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;150g salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;75g caster sugar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;About a kilo of duck fat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ground cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ground allspice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half a jar of marmalade&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;500ml vegetable or chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glass dry white wine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;40ml soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25ml mirin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;25ml Dijon mustard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;200ml freshly squeezed orange juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;One onion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;50g butter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starch granules (or for the less lazy than me, half a floury potato diced really fine)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Four handfuls of red or wild rice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Method&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, first up, you&amp;rsquo;ll be desiccating your duck legs. Since most desiccants are not in the slightest bit tasty, the tradition here is sea salt, which (being hygroscopic) does the job excellently. During this process, we&amp;rsquo;ll be taking the opportunity to get some interesting flavours into the meat as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dice your half head of garlic, set it aside. You&amp;rsquo;ll need it in a bit, but it&amp;rsquo;s a nice easy start, and we all like that, right? Besides, it smells awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get yourself a box like this:
&lt;img src=&#34;http://jamieduerden.co.uk/images/2015/08/IMG_20150821_204639-1-.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important factors here: it seals, and it has the rack in the bottom to give it a bit of space underneath the meat. Arrange your duck legs artistically in the box, and then sprinkle salt (all of it), juniper berries, the caster sugar, that garlic you shredded, and lots of ground black pepper (use an actual grinder. I&amp;rsquo;m sure you don&amp;rsquo;t own the powdered stuff, but just in case&amp;hellip;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it gets boring for a while. Seal up the box, hide it in the fridge for a couple of days. Yup, days. Blame kinetics, this is a slow process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back already? Excellent. Preheat the oven to about 390K. Grab your box, which should now have a slurry of salty, sugary duck-water on the bottom, and retrieve the duck legs. If they quack, you need to leave them in a bit longer. Rinse the salt and flavourings off, and set them in a casserole dish. Needs to be a fairly tight fit, so don&amp;rsquo;t go overboard on dish diameter. Dust with cinnamon, allspice and pepper, then cover with the duck fat. You&amp;rsquo;ll need more than you think; the legs need to be completely submerged in molten fat. If you&amp;rsquo;re watching your weight, don&amp;rsquo;t worry (also, why are you here?), you won&amp;rsquo;t be eating all of it. Casserole dish needs a lid, then makes its way to the oven for about three hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the sauce, start by heating up the marmalade, stock, wine and orange juice to a simmer. Use a whisk to stir, it helps dissolve the marmalade faster. Once the marmalade is dissolved, add the butter, soy sauce, mirin, mustard, the starch source, and the onion (diced). Raise to a boil, lower to a simmer, and reduce until you have about half a pint of fairly thick sauce. Shortly before serving, pour through a sieve into a jug, taking care not to get too much on the floor. A funnel helps here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wild rice takes about 25-30 minutes to cook, but I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume you know how to boil rice, so just start early enough and all is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the duck legs are sufficiently tender that a fork will pass through them with no resistance, (no, that solid bit is bone, try a different angle) extract them from the oven, recover from the fat, and place on a grill rack. Grill for about a minute, skin-side up, just to get the skin crispy. Watch carefully, because it will go black &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; fast due to the sugar we soaked into the skin in the first step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Per plate; duck leg, rice, sauce over all, plus whatever greens you choose. Swiss chard goes well, as would red cabbage.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
