<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>New Experiences on Not So Fungible </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>https://jamieduerden.co.uk/tags/new-experiences/</link>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    
    
    <updated>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 12:17:05 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Brief Foray into Archaeology</title>
      <link>https://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/a-brief-foray-into-archaeology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2015 12:17:05 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/a-brief-foray-into-archaeology/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A few&lt;/strong&gt; weeks ago I was made aware by a friend that the Surrey Community Archaeology Unit are doing a dig not too far from my house. In the spirit of inquiry (I&amp;rsquo;ve never been part of an excavation before), I volunteered to assist. It&amp;rsquo;s on the site of a military camp, erected for WWI, torn down in 1920, then re-established for WWII and finally removed around 1949. Since then the land has been managed by Natural England, so other than dog walkers not much has disturbed it, resulting in a rapid return to woodland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bearing in mind that this whole area was completely clear on both sides of the current A3 route in about 1950, with concrete and rubble all over, I&amp;rsquo;m quite impressed with the takeover by bracken and oak trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The survey was done by another group of volunteers some time previously, and they identified a number of locations which might prove interesting, based on the location of the military huts in the drawings. This led to much wandering around pointing at sections of undifferentiated woodland and trying to match them to hand-drawn maps and estimates of &amp;lsquo;we walked about this far&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day one, eight volunteers turned up, plus the three professional archaeologists from the SCAU. The site for Trench One was identified, and the bracken attacked with strimmers and machetes. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t taking many photographs at that point, but other people were[^n].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cleared, we de-turfed, we mattocked. Principle discovery: mattocks are heavy, steel toes are vital equipment. Most of the finds were bottle glass, coal, and crushed slag - this latter one was a bit worrying, because that&amp;rsquo;s used for filling trenches, and that area also reacted to the current meter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did find a few interesting bits: one empty .303 shell casing, unfired (no strike on the primer), one .303 jacketed bullet (fired, rifling marks still visible), and one .303 training round, with no primer cup, its wooden bullet rotted away, and six holes in the casing so you could tell it couldn&amp;rsquo;t go &amp;lsquo;bang&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trench One was thus abandoned at the end of the day, and will (sans tools, of course) look like this until made good: &lt;img src=&#34;https://jamieduerden.co.uk/images/2015/07/IMG_20150719_142255.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;That grey smear halfway up is the stuff we didn&#39;t want to dig through&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Day two, same set of people. I didn&amp;rsquo;t arrive until lunchtime due to other commitments, but joined in with Trench Two at around midday. This yielded some window glass, some coal, several bottle pieces including what our bottle expert declared to be the neck of a lemonade bottle, cork included, and half a pair of nineties plastic sunglasses in three pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having cleared and brushed clean Trench Two, we wandered over to see what the other half of the group had been doing in Trench Three. Attempts were clearly being made to dig a canal. &lt;img src=&#34;https://jamieduerden.co.uk/images/2015/07/IMG_20150720_154702.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Canal?&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were about six colours of very soft, uncompacted sand coming out of that mound, plus a band of charcoal and burned rocks; given the bullet found shortly after excavation commenced it&amp;rsquo;s possible this was used as a backstop for target practice, but it&amp;rsquo;s not tall enough for that to have been its primary purpose, if indeed there was a purpose. Uncertainty remains whether the mound of sand is intentional or a natural feature, but opinion among the three professionals in the group is that it&amp;rsquo;s probably just natural. We&amp;rsquo;ll know tomorrow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around the level of the burned section, they did disinter an intact stoneware ginger beer bottle from 1921. &lt;img src=&#34;https://jamieduerden.co.uk/images/2015/07/IMG_20150720_153823.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://jamieduerden.co.uk/images/2015/07/IMG_20150720_154639.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://jamieduerden.co.uk/images/2015/07/IMG_20150720_154644.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given the area was basically just a nice green bit off the A3 at that time, this probably indicates picnickers rather than a military taste for ginger beer. Day two thus wrapped up cheerfully, with tea and tiffin consumed by all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, I had to skip the rest of the week due to a combination of real work and torrential rain; there are further weeks arranged for August, so hopefully I shall have the opportunity to return to the dig site then.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single-Cylinder Engines (and grease)</title>
      <link>https://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/single-cylinder-engines-and-grease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 19:56:10 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamieduerden.co.uk/post/single-cylinder-engines-and-grease/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been&lt;/strong&gt; saying for a while that it would be an excellent idea for me to learn how to clean and maintain internal combustion engines. First because they&amp;rsquo;re interesting, and my knowledge of them has been limited to diagrams&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fc8ea34896daa2166d286ba54a4cd5d9:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:fc8ea34896daa2166d286ba54a4cd5d9:1&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, and second because at some point I&amp;rsquo;d like to own a Series 3 Land Rover or early Defender, which is sort of pointless unless I can maintain it myself.&lt;sup class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; id=&#34;fnref:fc8ea34896daa2166d286ba54a4cd5d9:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a rel=&#34;footnote&#34; href=&#34;#fn:fc8ea34896daa2166d286ba54a4cd5d9:2&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for me, we had a spare IC-powered strimmer in the garage. Sitting empty and unused (partly because it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t start) for about two decades, it was the perfect &lt;del&gt;victim&lt;/del&gt; learning tool; a single cylinder, spark-plug ignition petrol engine, with flywheel. About eight moving parts, and as simple as these things get. I decided that rather than find a manual, I&amp;rsquo;d just dismantle it as far as possible, and try to divine the purpose of each element. Once cleaned and reassembled (and repaired, if I could work out what the problem was), I could check my accuracy by seeing if it would run.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First things first: removing the &amp;lsquo;strimmer&amp;rsquo; bit from the engine. This turned out to be a matter of two machine screws; the attachment is a square peg and socket arrangement, caked in grease but otherwise trivial.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having set that aside (not needed for this investigation), I set about dismantling the main body of the engine. The coupling between the engine and the attachment socket was fascinating; a spring, retaining a pair of heavy and well lubricated semicircular weights. These fit inside a cup on the coupling, and would only make contact when spinning fast enough to spread under rotational forces. I think this is so that when manually starting the engine, the weight of the strimmer itself is disconnected. It should also mean that if the strimmer head is jammed, the drive shaft can still rotate freely - given that the housing here was half filled with a mixture of oil and metal shavings, this must have happened a fair bit over the lifetime of the engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next step was to remove the petrol tank. The cap is severely broken, with the threaded section detached from the &amp;lsquo;cap&amp;rsquo; bit, so I will have to either source another or repair this one with some glue that is not soluble in petroleum spirits. Maybe Araldite? A problem for reassembly. This was also set aside, and the fuel line examined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here I discovered the second problem. The fuel filter was perished; the remnants of a black foam disc which when removed from the fuel line fell into two pieces, and while lying on the workbench dissolved utterly into an oily liquid. I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure that means it needed replacing, and may well have been why it wasn&amp;rsquo;t running in the first place. The air filter was similarly perished, though less damp, and simply crumbled to dust as I removed it from the air intake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing the cylinder revealed a slightly burned and uneven piston head (I&amp;rsquo;ll need to clean that with a wire brush, I think), but otherwise all seemed in good order. Other than the filters, I can&amp;rsquo;t see a reason this engine wasn&amp;rsquo;t running. The remainder (the flywheel, casing, spark plug and associated circuitry, and pull-cord mechanism) came apart relatively easily, and no problems were evident with any of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts are currently degreasing; I&amp;rsquo;ll scrub them all clean, work out which bits are supposed to be oiled and give them their necessary lubrication, and reassemble with new fuel and air filters. Hopefully the next post (with photographs, this time) on this will be when it&amp;rsquo;s running!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://jamieduerden.co.uk/images/2015/07/engine-parts.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34;&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fc8ea34896daa2166d286ba54a4cd5d9:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://28oa9i1t08037ue3m1l0i861.wpengine.netdna-cdn.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/05/img11.gif&#34;&gt;A helpful diagram&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fc8ea34896daa2166d286ba54a4cd5d9:1&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:fc8ea34896daa2166d286ba54a4cd5d9:2&#34;&gt;This will also necessitate learning to weld. That will probably be a future blog post, or several.
 &lt;a class=&#34;footnote-return&#34; href=&#34;#fnref:fc8ea34896daa2166d286ba54a4cd5d9:2&#34;&gt;&lt;sup&gt;[return]&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
